Guide to the Herman F. Mark Collection RG.002
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series IV: Publications, 6464
  - Subseries A: Publication lists, undated; 9055
    - Herman Mark publication lists, 1922-1992, undated; 9056 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Publications of H. Mark, undated; 9057 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Herman Mark OCLC holdings, 1986 June 20; 9058 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Lists of reports and books, undated; 9059 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Published Polymer Symposia lists, undated; 9526 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Supplements and addenda to publication lists, undated; 9060 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Articles by Herman Mark, 6465
    - Über den Bau des kristallisierten Anteils der Cellulose II [The Structure of the Crystallized Components of Cellulose], 1928; 6485 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Ein Beitrag zur Konstitution der Stärke [Constitution of Starch]. Kurt Meyer, Heinrich Hopff, and Herman Mark, 1929; 6484 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Dir Stuktur der Zellulose und ihre technische Auswirkung [The Structure of Cellulose and its Technical Importance], 1929; 6486 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Vorgange bei der mechanischen Verformung von Kautschuk [Process of the Mechanical Deformation of Rubber]. Mark and Valko, 1930; 6487 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Phenomena of the Mechanical Deformation of Rubber, 1930, August-September; 9009 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Die Experimentellen und Theoretischen Grundlagen der Elaktronenbeugung, 1931; 6596 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Die Viskosität von Lösungen, Besonders von Lösungen Hochmolekularer Stoffe, 1933; 6490 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Zur innermolekularen Statistic, insbesondere bei Kettenmolekulen I, 1934 October 18; 9010 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Ergebnisse der Exakten Naturwissenschaften, 1936; 9037 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Die Elastizität Des Kautschuks und ihr Zusammenhang mit dem Strukturmodell, 1937; 6491 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Über die Entstehung und Eigenschaften Hochpolymerer Festkörper, 1937; 6492 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Ein Ausblick auf die Hochpolymere Chemie, 1938; 9031 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Fortschritte der Chemie organischer Naturstoffe, 1938; 9039 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Natural and Artificial Rubber: The Elasticity of Long - Chain Molecules, 1938; 6493 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Intermicellar Hole and Tube System in Fiber Structure, 1939; 6494 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Composite Elasticity of Rubber - I, 1940 June 1; 9033 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Elasticity of Natural and Synthetic Rubber, 1940; 9036 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Relation Between Chain Length Distribution Curve and Tenacity, 1941 July 17; 9032 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - The Structure of Cellulose Fibers, 1941; 6495 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Structure and Mechanical Behavior of Highpolymers, 1941; 9030 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Some Applications of the Kinetic Theory to the Behavior of Long Chain Compounds, 1941; 6496 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Alkaline Purification of Cellulose, 1942; 9022 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - A Statistical Treatment of Crystallization Phenomena in High Polymers, 1942; 6497 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Phase Transition and Elastic Bahavior of High Polymers, 1942; 6498 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Intermolecular Forces and Mechanical Behavior of High Polymers, 1942; 6499 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Stickiness, Tackiness, and Spinnability, 1942 April 1; 9023 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Improved X-Ray Technique for the Study of Natural and Synthetic Fibers, 1943 July-October; 9034 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Osmotic Pressure and Viscosity Measurements with Cellulose Acetate Fractions, 1943; 6500 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - On the Mechanism of Inhibition of Styrene Polymerization, 1943 November; 9038 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Comparative Osmotic and Viscosity Measurements with Polystyrene Fractions, 1943; 6501 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Recent Results on the Kinetics and Elementary Steps of Polyreactions, 1943 November 12; 9024 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Some Scientific Aspects of the Synthetic Rubber Problem, 1943 April; 9035 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - X-Ray Studies of Chain Polymers, 1944 April; 9029 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Molecular-Size Distribution of Cross-Linked Polystyrene, 1945; 6502 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Polymerization of Olefins and Diolefins in Suspension and Emulsion. Part I, 1946; 6503 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Polymerization of Olefins and Diolefins in Suspension and Emulsion. Part II, 1946; 6504 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Creep Behavior of Plasticized Vinylite VYNW, 1947; 6505 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Rate of Exchange of Cellulose with Heavy Water, 1948; 6506 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Molecular Weight Investigation of High Polymers with the Electron Microscope, 1949; 6507 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Osmotic Measurements of Isomeric Polyvinyl Isobutyl Ethers, 1949; 6508 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Viskositat und Molekulargewicht makromolekularer Losungen, 1949; 9049 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Copolymerization, 1950; 9041 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Monatshefte für Cheme, 1950; 6509 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Inhibition of Friedel-Crafts Polymerization. 1. The Mechanism of Inhibition, 1950; 9028 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - The Effect of Oxygen on the Physical and Chemical Properties of Polymers, 1950; 9040 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Biological Significance of Folding and Unfolding Protein Molecules, 1951 May 5; 9046 (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Synthesis of Macromolecules with Long Range Periodicities, 1951; 6510 (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Mischpolymerisation II, 1951 November 15; 9027 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Osmotic, Viscometric, and Turbidity Studies of Polystyrene in Mixed Solvents, March 1951; 9047 (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - High Temperature Osmometry of Polymer Solution, 1952; 6511 (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - Report on the Shear Dependence of the Intrinsic Viscosity of Cellulose Nitrate Solutions, 1952 April 14; 9050 (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - Viskositätszahl-Molekulargewichts-Beziehung Für Cellulose Und Untersuchungen Von Nitrocellulose in Verschieden Lösungsmitteln, 1952; 6512 (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - Effect of Strains on Heat Distortion, 1953 November; 9054 (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Report on Molecular-Weight Measurements of Standard Polystyrene Samples, 1953 February; 9048 (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - The Production of Organic Free Radicals by Light, 1953; 6513 (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - The Synthesis and Applicability of Block and Graft Copolymers, 1953; 6514 (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - New Types of Membranes for Osmotic Pressure Measurements, 1954; 6515 (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Molecular Engineer, 1955; 6597 (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - Über Pfropf-und Block-Mischpolymere Aus Synthetische und Natürlichen Makromolekülen, 1955; 6516 (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Makromolekule mit mehreren Bindungsarten, 1955; 9026 (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Nuove gomme, nuove materie plastiche e nuove fibre, 1955 January; 9042 (Box 11, Folder 67)
    - Prof. Kurt G. Stern, 1956 March 24; 9025 (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - Radiation Chemistry and Wood, 1956 April 8-13; 9043 (Box 11, Folder 69)
    - Synthesis of Vinyl Type Polymers with Coordination Catalysts, 1956; 6517 (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - Theorie und Molekulare Deutung Technologischer Eigenschaften von Hochpolymerer Werkstoffen, 1956; 9051 (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - Organic Plastics as Conductors and Semiconductors, 1957; 6518 (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - Losungseigenschaften isotaktischer Polymerer, 1957; 9044 (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - A Few Principles of Adhesion, 1957; 6519 (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - Giant Molecules, 1957; 6520 (Box 11, Folder 75)
    - Progress in the Field of High Polymers, 1957; 9045 (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - Soviet Polymer Science Today, 1958 July; 9052 (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - A Convenient Laboratory Preperation of Isotactic Polystyrene, 1959; 6521 (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - Fortschritte auf dem Gebiet der Hochpolymeren in USA, 1959; 9053 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Thermisch Resistente Polymere, 1960; 6522 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - Sonderdruck Aus Der Zeitschrift>>Kunststoffe, 1960; 6523 (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - Recent Developments in the Field of High Polymers, 1960; 6524 (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - Cleavage of Disulfide Polymers. I. By Inorganic Sulfides*, 1961; 6525 (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - Künftige Entwicklungsrichtlinien zur Verbesserung der Kohäsionsund Adhäsionsfestigkeit von Polymeren, 1962; 6526 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - Future Trends For Improvement of Ashesive Strength of Polymers, 1962; 6527 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - New Resins for Electrical Applications, 1962; 6528 (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Future Trends for Improvement of Cohesive and Adhesive Strength of Polymers, 1962; 6598 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - Inhibition of Radical Polymerization in Liquid Sulfer Dioxide by Alkali Iodide and Dimethylsuldoxide, 1962; 6529 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - Structure and Properties of Polymeric Materials, 1963; 6530 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    - Cleavage of Disulfide Polymers. II. By Thiols*, 1963; 6531 (Box 11, Folder 90)
    - Report on our Observations of South American Countries, 1964; 6532 (Box 11, Folder 91)
    - Synthesis and Application of New Polymers, 1964; 6533 (Box 11, Folder 92)
    - Polymers- Past, Present, Future, 1964; 6534 (Box 11, Folder 93)
    - Tailor-Making Plastics, 1964; 6535 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - Stereospecific Polymerization, 1965; 6599 (Box 11, Folder 95)
    - Report on Copolymerization, 1965; 6536 (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - Techniques de L'ingenieur, 1965; 6537 (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - Polymere Als Baumaterialien, 1966; 6538 (Box 11, Folder 98)
    - New Concepts - New Polymers - New Applications, 1967; 6579 (Box 11, Folder 99)
    - The Nature of Polymeric Materials, 1967; 6540 (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - Some Quantitative Consideration on Spinning, 1967; 6541 (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Synthetic Polymers in Medical Sciences, 1968; 6542 (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Fibras De Celulosa, 1968; 6543 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - Polymer Science in the Prevention of Air Pollution, 1969; 9527 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Diffusion and Reaction of Polymers in a Capillary Matrix, 1969; 6544 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Some Quantitative Considerations on Spinning, 1970; 6600 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Bulletinul Institutului Politechnic, 1970; 6545 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Vortragszyklus-Umweltschutz, 1971; 6546 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Polymeric Conductors and Semiconductors, 1972; 6601 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - What Next in Man-Made Fibers?, 1972; 6547 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - The Early Days of Polymer Science, 1973; 6548 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Quantitative Betrachtungen Uber Das Schmelzspinnen, 1973; 6549 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Discursos Del Acto De La Solemne Investidura de Doctores, 1974; 6550 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Polymers in the Next Decade, 1974; 6551 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Polymeric Materials: Natural and Synthetic, 1974; 6552 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Contemporary Topics in Polymer Sciences, 1974; 6553 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Visit to China in June, 1972, 1974; 6554 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Polymers in the Next Decades, 1974; 6555 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Aromatic Polymers, 1974; 6602 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Combustion of Polymers and its Retardation, 1975; 6603 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Komfort und Hygiene der Kleidung(Cernia, Mark, Atlas), 6604 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Polymer Progress--Worldwide, 1975; 6556 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Polimery Organiczne a Srodowisko, 1975; 6557 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Verfahrenstechnik Technische Chemie Apparatewesen, 1975; 6558 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Current Developments for Polymeric Materials, 1976; 6559 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Cellulose- Past, Present and Future, 1976; 6560 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Polymers as Building Materials, 1976; 6561 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Polymers as Materials, 1976; 6562 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Catalysis in Polymerization, 1976; 6586 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Introduction to Polymer Science, 1977; 6563 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Contemporary Topics in Polymer Science Volume I Macromolecular Science Retrospect and Prospect, 6564 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Reprint From Proceedings of the 5th European Symposium on Polymer Spectroscopy in Cologn, September 78, 1978; 6565 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Polymers for the Future, 1978; 6566 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - So Plannten Wir Den Aufbau des Weizmann-Institus[The Planning of the Weizmann Institute], 1980; 6595 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Fifty Years of Cellulose Research, 1980; 6568 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Aus den Fruhen Tagen der Makromolekularen Chemie, 1980; 6569 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Why Perkin Succeeded: Perkin Medal Address, 1980; 6570 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Rehovot, 1980; 6578 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Cellulose Chemistry and Technology, 1980; 6585 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Macromolecular Chemistry Today-Aging Roots, Sprouting Branches, 1981; 6571 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Chemical Education, 1981; 6577 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Coming to an Age of Polymers in Science and Technology, 1981; 6587 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Polymers for Extreme Service Conditions, 1981; 6589 (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Principles of Elastomer Synthesis, 1984; 6572 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Chemtech, 1984; 6593 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - The Development of Plastics, 1984; 6588 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - New Elastomers by Choice, Not Chance, 1984; 6573 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - A Century of Polymer Science and Technology, 1985; 6581 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - A Tale of Two Fibers: A Productive Interaction of Physics and Chemistry, 1985; 6590 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Textile and Engineering: Present and Future, 1987; 6594 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Applied Polymer Science - A Forecast, 1987; 6584 (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - Polymers to the Year 2000 and Beyond: A Forecast, 1988; 9528 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Polymers in Materials Science, 1990; 6574 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Advanced Materials, 1990; 6576 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Corrections of Some Miscommunications on the Development and Present Status of Rubber Elasticity (Guth+Mark), 1990; 6591 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Cellulose Chemistry and Technology, 1990; 6592 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Subseries C: Articles about Herman Mark, 6467
    - Chemical and Engineering News, 1948 Novermber 1; 9066 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Molecular Engineer, 1955 April 2; 9067 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Polymers Everywhere I inThe New Yorker (with correspondence), 1958 September 13; 1957 October 2; 9064 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - The New Yorker Sept. 20, 1957 with Polymers Everywhere II, 1958 September 20; 9065 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Polymers Everywhere I & II, pasted on paper, 1958; 9063 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Great American Scientists: The Chemists in Fortune Magazine, 1960 April; 9068 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Great American Scientists: The Chemists in Fortune Magazine (oversize copy), 1960 April; 9069 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Plastic Pioneer in New York Post, 1975 April 30; 9070 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - A Declaration in The Chemist, 1976 July; 9071 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Harvey Prizes to Chemist and Talmudic Scholar, 1976 June 21; 9072 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Zur Geschichte der makromolekularen Chemie, 1979; 9079 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Polymersymposien, 1980; 9075 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Pioneers of Polymers, 1981; 9529 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Expert Cites Polymer "Explosion" in The Indianapolis Star, 1983 October 18; 9074 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Herman Mark and the Structure of Crystals, 1984 June; 9076 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - That Was The War in The New Yorker, 1985 August 12; 9062 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Polymer Pioneer Herman Mark Wins Case's Top Science Award, 1989 April 29; 9077 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Brooklyn Poly's Mark: Master of molecules, undated; 9073 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Significant Contributions of H. Mark in Polymer Science, undated; 9078 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper clippings and photocopies, 1963-1989; 1966-1969; 9080 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Subseries D: Polymers and plastics, 6470
    - "Uber Polymerisation" by H. Staudinger, 1920; 9083 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - "Zur Kenntnis der Cellulose" by K. Freudenberg, 1921 February 9; 9081 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - "Uber hochpolymere Verbindungen" by H. Staudinger and W. Heuer, 1929 December; 9087 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - "The New Breed of Plastics" by F. Bello, 1957 November; 9119 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - "The Nylon Rope Trick: Demonstration of Condensation Polymerization" by P. Morgan and S. Kwolek, 1959 April; 9103 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Polymer Symposia No. 6: Thermal Analysis of High Polymers, 1963 September; 9129 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - "Von Emmil Fischer zur molekularen Konstitution der Cellulose und Starke" by K. Freudenberg, 1967; 9082 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - "Final Report on Man-Made Fiber Industry in Taiwan" by E. Braunsteiner, 1968-1969; 9092 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - "Petrochemistry and the Man-Made Fibre Industry in the Developing Countries" by E. Braunsteiner, 1969 October 31; 9093 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - "Final Report on Modern Polymer Science and Technology of Polyvinyl Chloride" by E. Braunsteiner, 1970; 9115 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - "A Comparison of Some Electrophotographic Processes Based on Photoconductor-Insulation Layer Combinations" by P. Mark, 1974 May/June; 9114 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Request from the Government of India for the production of synthetic fibres (Nylon and Polyester), circa 1974; 9116 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - "Rayon: Veteran Fiber is 'in' Again" and other articles on engineered fibers in Chemicalweek, 1979 June 6; 9086 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Commemorazione del membro effettivo Giulio Natta, 1980; 9118 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - DuPont's Group Transfer Polymerization (with correspondence and press release), 1983 August 31; 9111 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - DuPont Group Transfer Polymerization chemical sketches and transparencies, 1983; 9112 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - DuPont Group Transfer Polymerization articles, 1983; 9113 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - "Polymer Chemistry - Where Are We Going?" by M.L. Good, 1985 October 24; 9106 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Reprints from the Encyclopedia of Materials Science and Engineering, 1986; 9110 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Polymer symposia, 1986, 1992; 9131 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - "The Nylon Drama" by D. Hounshell and J. Smith, 1988; 9085 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - "Chemical and Mechanical Evaluation on Healing Mechanism of Asphalt Concrete" by Y. R. Kim, 1989 October; 9101 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - "Strong Growth for Reinforcing Fibres" by S. Davies, 1990 January; 9098 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - "Signs Point to Slowdown for European Chemical Industry in 1990", 1990 March 5; 9100 (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - "Conductive Polymers" M. Kanatzidis, 1990 December 3; 9105 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - "Pressure for Plastic Recycling Prompts a Mix of Tough Laws and Cooperation" by R. Smith, 1990; 9099 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Polymers for Advanced Technologies, 1990; 9109 (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - GE Plastics: Living Environments brochures, circa 1990; 9096 (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - Advances in Degradable Polymers - International Herman F. Mark Symposium, 1992; 9128 (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - History and etymology of polymers and plastics, 1994, 2003; 9095 (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - Eli Pearce, 2002; 9094 (Box 13, Folder 53)
    - Polyethylene, undated; 9107 (Box 13, Folder 54)
    - "A History of Polyolefins" by H. Sailors and J. Hogan, undated; 9108 (Box 13, Folder 55)
    - Sections VII and VIII on Staudinger and Farben by Udo Tschimmel, undated; 9117 (Box 13, Folder 56)
    - SWP synthetic fiber from Crown Zellerbach, undated; 9102 (Box 13, Folder 57)
    - Chapter 8: Aliphatic Polyethers, by S. Inoue and T. Aida, undated; 9120 (Box 13, Folder 58)
    - Chapter 10: Poly(acetal)s, by H. Gorrisen, undated; 9121 (Box 13, Folder 59)
    - Book section in German (title unknown), undated; 9084 (Box 13, Folder 60)
    - Articles on microfiche, undated; 9061 (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Subseries E: Physics and chemistry, 9089
    - "Abstract Vector Spaces Applied to Problems in Detection and Estimation Theory" by M. Schwartz, 1966 July; 9091 (Box 13, Folder 62)
    - Great Moments in Chemistry, 1969 April; 9088 (Box 13, Folder 63)
    - "Facts and Figures for Chemical R&D" by B. Hileman, 1990 August 20; 9097 (Box 13, Folder 64)
    - "Unified Theories of Elementary-Particle Interaction" by S. Weinberg, undated; 9104 (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - "The Use of the Method of Maximum Likelihood in Estimating Continuous-Modulated Intelligence which has been Corrupted by Noise" by D. Youla, undated; 9090 (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - Subseries F: Hans Mark, 6471
    - Publications by Hans Mark, 1981-2004; 1981-1988; 9123 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Sixty Years of Polymers in Brooklyn (transparencies), undated; 9124 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Hans Mark and Polytechnic, 2007, undated; 9125 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Interviews with and articles about Hans Mark, 1984-1990; 9126 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Trade publications, 1981-1988; 9127 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Subseries G: Monographs and notebooks, 6483
    - H.F.M Diary, 1950; 9170 (Box 15, Item 1)
    - Mark address book, undated; 9171 (Box 15, Item 2)
    - Mark address book, undated; 9172 (Box 15, Item 3)
    - "Formelsammlung und Repetitorium der Mathematik," by O. Burklen, 1918; 9148 (Box 15, Item 4)
    - Various German articles, bound, 1924; 9161 (Box 15, Item 5)
    - Various German articles, bound, undated; 9162 (Box 15, Item 6)
    - Various German articles, bound (articles numbered by Mark), undated; 9167 (Box 15, Item 7)
    - "The Phenomena of Polymerisation and Condensation: A General Discussion," by The Faraday Society, 1936; 9164 (Box 15, Item 8)
    - "Collected Papers of Wallance Hume Carothers on High Polymeric Substances" ed. by H. Mark and G. Whitby, 1940; 9166 (Box 15, Item 9)
    - "Advances in Colloid Science, Volume II" ed. by H. Mark and G. Whitby, 1946; 9163 (Box 15, Item 10)
    - "Advances in Colloid Science, Volume III" ed. by H. Mark and E Verwey, 1950; 9165 (Box 15, Item 12)
    - "Etat Acuel de la Chimie et de la Physique des Molecules Geantes" by H. Mark, 1950; 9168 (Box 15, Item 13)
    - "Polymer Reviews" by N. Gaylord and H. Mark, 1959; 9169 (Box 15, Item 14)
    - "Condensation Polymers: Interfacial and Solution Methods" by P. Morgan, 1965; 9160 (Box 15, Item 15)
    - Offprint from Perspectives in American History, Volume II, 1968; 9158 (Box 15, Item 16)
    - "Flame -Retardant Polymeric Materials" Ed. by M. Lewin, S. Atlas, and E. Pearce, 1978; 9159 (Box 15, Item 17)
    - "Polymer Science Overview: A Tribute to Herman F. Mark" by G. Stahl, 1980 August; 9156 (Box 15, Item 18)
    - "The Limits of Science" by P. Medawar, with note to H. Mark, 1984; 9155 (Box 15, Item 19)
    - "An Exploration of Patients' Experience in the Recovery Room" by Catherine Mark, 1986; 9151 (Box 15, Item 20)
    - "Polymer Pioneers" by P. Morris, 1986; 9149 (Box 15, Item 21)
    - "A Career in Composites" by C. Yates, 1988 July; 9150 (Box 15, Item 22)
    - "Center of Macromolecular Design for Advanced Technology" A proposal prepared for the Nation Science Foundation, 1988 January 15; 9152 (Box 15, Item 23)
    - "Maurits Dekker: A Celebration of a Life 1899-1995" by MDeye, 1995 December; 9157 (Box 15, Item 24)
    - "Nucleation and Crystallization of Polymers" Dissertation by Karthigeyan Nagarajan, 2000 January; 9153 (Box 15, Item 25)
    - "Erzalungen und Marchen" by Oscar Wilde, undated; 9154 (Box 15, Item 26)
    - PINY binder: The Stereo Rubbers, undated; 9145 (Box 16, Item 1)
    - PINY binder: Olefin Copolymers, undated; 9146 (Box 16, Item 2)
    - PINY binder: Viscoelastic Behavior of Solution Rubbers, undated; 9147 (Box 16, Item 3)
    - "Der feste Korper" by R. Sanger, 1938; 9175 (Box 16, Item 4)
    - "Langenscheidts Taschenworterbuch" by H. Menge and H. Muller, 1955; 9173 (Box 16, Item 5)